Venkata Sandeep Kumar Karamsetty

Mobile: 0479155146

Email: venkatasandeepkumarkaramsetty@gmail.com

Personal Portfolio: https://karamsetty09.github.io/karamsetty.github.io/

Linkedin

Professional Profile

Experienced Software Engineer with over 4 years of experience working on full stack applications with various technologies. I possess strong problem-solving skills by always assessing the limitations of technologies to then build efficient software products. Currently seeking Software Engineering opportunities that focuses on adding new features to SaaS products.

Key Skills Summary

Programming Languages: Javascript, TypeScript, PHP, Python, SAP ABAP

Frameworks: React, React Native, Node JS, vue, Laravel

Database: SQL, MongoDB

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, REST

Version Control: Git, BitBucket

Certifications: freeCodeCamp - Responsive Web Design, SMART UOW - IOT handling with Nodejs

Employment Experience

Frontend Developer(Full-time)

Apr-2022 - current

V-DAQ - Building 239, Innovation Campus, Squires Way, North Wollongong, NSW 2500

- Working as a frontend developer using React.js and Typescript on frontend.
- Building UI/UX wireframes in Figma for both React and React-Native Applications.
- Developing, testing and adding features to react and react-Native applications on sprint cycle basis.
- Always delivering features along with jest and enzyme test-cases by adhering to test driven development.

Software Engineer(Full-time - Contract)

Aug 2021 - Feb 2022

Loopit - Level 24 Tower 3/300 Barangaroo Ave, Barangaroo NSW 2000

- Worked as a full stack developer using Vue.js with Typescript on frontend and PHP Laravel as backend.
- Tracking and fixing bugs with improvising jest testcases on frontend and phpunit testcases on backend.
- Adding new software features to the loopit platform by consulting, analysing, researching and evaluating system program needs, while working closely with the Product Managers, Technical Leads and other engineers
- Development and maintenance of code for technical solutions that fulfill system designs, functional and non-functional requirements, as stipulated by user stories
- Test-cases development, testing, debugging and bug-fixing for application within establishment testing protocols and peer reviewing standards to ensure that the application performs to required specifications
- Recognizing technology limitations and drawbacks in present systems and associated processes for providing required results by leveraging the resources of other technologies
- Optimize queries, indexes, stored procedures, and application logic to increase throughput, availability, scalability, redundancy, superior performance, and quick recoverability as applicable
- Adhering to good development practices: coding standards, documentation, code/design reviews, optimization and maintainability

Achievements:

- Recognition for Best feature released End of Month Reports,
- Complete Ownership of features released to Platform.

PHP Web Developer(Internship)

Apr 2021 - Jul 2021

Bannister Law - Suite 2, Level 9 Sydney - NSW

- Gather Software requirements and proposing best solution for the requirement
- Building Web applications as per the software requirements using technologies like Word-press, PHP, Docker and HTML, CSS, javaScript.
- Selecting best themes and plugins in word-press and customising them using PHP as per requirement needs
- Database creation and handling users sensitive data by using c-panel on server by backend and UI screens

Achievements:

Best Internal Asset Developer

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/karamsetty09/php-mysql-docker

PHP Web Developer(Part time)

Mar 2021 - Apr 2021

POLIXEN - Wollongong, Australia - NSW

- · Requirement analysis and creating design patterns to deliver best User Interface screens in blade.php
- UI screens creation by using PHP, Mysql and Javascript in Laravel framework
- Effective communication and coordination in team to deliver solutions on time
- Always open for suggestions to improvise my code as per requirements

Systems Engineer (Emp. ID - 713557)

Sep 2015 - Jun 2018

Infosys | Bangalore, India

- Completed generic and stream training with a percentage of 83, which involves Python, Sql & SAP ABAP
- Adding new features and handling bug fixes for applications built using Angular.
- Created Dashboards using **React** and **D3.js** for tracking **SAP Transport Requests**, So that higher management can track the amount of work done easily.
- · Built Authenticating system so that users can login to SAP environment for fetching data to Dashboard.
- Built and maintained Java Jenkins middleware as a Rest API to make all required data available to frontend React Application.
- Effective usage of javascript to handle validations for forms built for collecting user feedbacks.
- Worked in an Agile Team and actively participated in meetings for requirement gathering and developing the Applications.

Achievements

- Developer of the Quarter,
- Most Downloaded Tool Invoicing in SAP.

Personal Projects

React Applications - projects on github

- · Passionate about react application development, so built applications like: portfolio and table display with deletion feature.
- Developing Unit Tests by using jest for testing of applications.
- Transformable skills of using vue features like: Axios calls, state managements, events, unit tests etc, at loopit. As both technologies work on JavaScript.

GitHub Repository: https://karamsetty09.github.io/ReactTableDisplay/

Education

Professional Year Sep 2020 - Aug 2021

Performance Education, Sydney

Key Subjects: Australian Business Culture and Environment, Achieving Career Success, Australian Workplace Skills and Professional Business Communication

Master's Degree in Computer Science

Jul 2018 - Aug 2020

University of Wollongong, Australia

Dual – Specialization – Software Engineering & Machine Learning and Big Data

Graduated: 14th August 2020.

Bachelor's Degree in Electronics and Computer Engineering

Jun 2011 - May 2015

Koneru Lakshmaiah University, India

Graduated in First class with Distinction

Personal Attributes

- Proactive in taking new tasks and completing on time
- Adaptable to new challenges and learn new technologies to solve problems
- Confident in problem solving and planning for deadlines in software development
- Tutoring: Successfully conducted presentations explaining capabilities of tools developed in Infosys over VOIP

References

Rylan Kolb - Founder and Director at V-DAQ(North Wollongong)

Email: rylan@v-daq.com.au

+61 - 458795261

Jeremy Gupta - COO at Loopit.co(Sydney)

Email: jeremy.gupta@loopit.co

+61 - 416172725

James Oliver - Cloud Engineer at V-DAQ(North Wollongong)

Email: james.oliver3003@gmail.com